Okay, so we started looking at the TD learning
right, we look at TD(0) yes so what does TD(0)
do for us okay.
.
Yeah but it does essentially right, he does
evaluation right it just gives you given a
policy p and finds out what Vp is right and
use a sample backup and boot strap how do
we do control is the q function instead of
the v function that is it, what we do is fix
a policy p and use the q function and learn
the qp for the policy and then
max of that and then you get a new policy
and then you go ahead with it is it okay.
So that is one way of doing control with TD(0)
right so in fact I can do that v if I have
V but finding a greedy policy is hard so what
i can do is i can take the q function right,
so can you we want to write down how this
is going to look like what goes in here what
was in there I think so okay, so let us because
I put RT+1 we have to add the T everywhere
sorry, okay so first day I said as I put ST+1
AT+1 okay, so if you stop and think about
it what should really go here is right so
if you remember this is the
that is the current estimate, right that is
a target so this whole thing gives you a error
right.
So did I mention TD error in the last class
right, so this expression that you get in
the TD(0) update that expression is called
the TD error right, what does the TD error
RT+? V is Vo this T+1-Vo ST 1 that quantity
is called the TD error so I said it is some
error term so whatever error term you use
in the TD update is called the TD error and
the error term you would use in the Monte
Carlo update is called the Monte Carlo error
bla, bla whatever is one but TD error is the
more important things okay, so sometimes we
so the TD RF is special enough to get its
own symbol right, d so typically when I say
TD error d without any other quantification
it is the error on the v function okay, just
the more of a historic note so wherever I
use d I will define what d is but typically
delta by itself typically stands for the error
on the v function okay, good.
So ideally I want this why because I am using
this as my target and what is my target it
is expected return shafting from this point
right, that is the target since I do not have
the expected return I am using a sample return
which is what one Monte Carlo gave us as I
said instead of using a sample return I will
use bootstrapping to correct that written
so I will use the immediate reward plus ? times
that gives me the correct editor it is ideally
I should be using the return here but why
am I using the Q function
here yeah, so why am I using that just the
action i took a loan right ideally what should
i should have used that it's expectation over
my policy.
People see this is essentially equal to right
whatever is my current policy that is expect
so expected value of Q old comma stat plus
1 where AT plus 1 is taken according to the
current policy right so that is V but instead
of completing this expectation right I'm just
taking one sample from that expectation, that's
basically what I'm doing so if i apply this
rule often enough i will eventually compute
this expectation
by former cure, p you fire under that single
policy we are taking this salmon if you are
not updating the policy does not matter, if
you want to put the p here but since I am
fixed a policy I do not I do not worry about
it you should ask me this question envy it
makes more sense, but here there is another
reason why I am avoiding the p.
I will tell you in a minute right so we if
you give one to use people do not use Vp as
p,is fine right, so this is how we will estimate
q right so you understand why we are putting
in this here okay we are putting this here
as a estimate for this expectation right as
an unbiased estimate for this expectation
everyone with me okay good, so what do I do
now I won a few iterations of this learn the
Q function be greedy with respect to that
Q function and I can update my policy and
then run it again okay that is one way of
doing control okay.
There is another way of doing control well
this is exactly the same way whatever tell
you except that instead of running it for
several iterations with the same policy p
you take one step with that policy p update
the Q function and the next time you have
to choose an action be greedy with respect
to the current Q function, if you remember
we talked about this in generalized policy
iteration right you can just take one step
and then next time you can be greedy with
respect to that is that one update you've
done right, so do not fix a policy in this
sense in this case in so instead of having
a fixed policy every time you have to pick
an action we just look at the Q function and
pick the greedy action so this is like running
extreme generalized policy iteration, right.
So for every step you just take one step with
that policy for the next time step you be
greedy with respect to the value function
update, that you have done right you just
keep alternating between being greedy and
being and updating the value function you
just keep going back and forth for one step
update the value function next time you be
greedy right, so putting all of this together
you can actually get a algorithm like this
so you start off with arbitrary Q function
okay then right, so pickle action 80 to perform
in state according to the current q value
right so why'd I have put according to the
current Q value, you could just pick a greedy
action but we know from our bandit experience
being greedy always is a bad thing so you
need to do some kind of acceleration.
.
So you be greedy a lot okay explore right
so you can either do this with some kind of
a epsilon greedy kind of an approach right
or you can do softmax or you can do anything
whatever, whatever takes your fancy come up
with a good exploration strategy right so
people do Bayesian exploration and there are
many different ways optimal ways in which
to do this exploration, right. Now apply 80
and your sample St+1 Rt+1T right, you could
sample this if you have a sample model you
could just run this through simulation or
you could just perform it in the real world
and get the St+1 Rt+1, right.
Now comes the important thing pick 80+1 according
to the q function okay, the current q function,
now what you do
and keep doing this until your episode terminates
right, if once episode terminates then you
go back to kind is not and keep doing this
again and again until you are happy with your
q function, okay right fine you do not agree.
So there is no explicit evaluation stage there
is no explicit gratification stage right,
so the evaluation is done here right and the
gratification is done here right, here, okay.
There are some small caveats here so if you
want this algorithm to converge to something
right what do you think you should do and
then anything else decrease alpha also over
time right, so decreased alpha over time decreased
epsilon over time so that eventually you will
stop updating things but the eventualities
should happen a long, long, long time into
the future right, so you should explore a
lot, right so that you are sampled every state
action often enough and at alpha should not
decay so quickly that even while you are sampling
if alpha goes to zero then there is no point
in sampling right.
So the alpha also should not decay till you
have sample enough okay, so both should decade
but should be decaying at a slower alpha should
decay at a slower rate than epsilon, okay
is it good okay. So this is probably the second
most popular reinforcement learning algorithm
that is used for solving a lot of problems
so this is called anyone SARSA.
So what is SARSA okay, sounds like a Mexican
dish or a dance so it is a dumbest possible
explanation for the name okay, state action
reward next state next action so you need
the next action also before you can perform
these updates therefore they called it SARSA
right, the name stuck I mean and we have reached
certain to blame for it I mean he came up
with the name not the guys who originally
proposed this algorithm okay, so they are
in come up with this names so the guys are
Rummery and Nurujan.
So in fact couple of years ago Nurujan was
going to come and spend like a semester here
on a sabbatical from England but then last
minute he changed his mind so you never made
it the guy who proposed SARSA who going to
come and spend a semester here but he did
not come anyway, so this is SARSA this is
an on policy algorithm why, because I am following
this epsilon greedy policy but I am also updating
the value function corresponding to the epsilon
greedy policy, right.
Because I amusing the action that was actually
taken, right so if you go back here this will
be the expected value according to p which
is whatever p I am following, right so only
for that is this a sampler correct right,
there for this is on policy algorithm, okay.
In fact if we stop and think about it for
a second in fact I can complete this expectation
without knowing anything about the world.
No, the expectation is only with respect to
i and the quantity and taking the expectation
of is qp, right I know both p because that
is as policy for according to which I am taking
actions, right, and I know the cube because
that is a quantity I am estimating anyway
so I might as well compute this expectation
explicitly I do not have to take a sample
from further expectation here in fact I can
do the exact computation so if this line I
can replace with something like this.
That is why I said it is computing the epsilon
greedy value, since you are updating for the
exploration steps as well it is actually computing
the policy correspondent value function corresponding
to the epsilon greedy version if epsilon GD
policy and that is why I also call it on policy
right, so you could do something like this
right. So in this case there are a couple
of interesting things here I do not have to
pick an action A priori right, so here we
first pick the action for 80+1right.
And then we did the updating and the way I
have written the loop you notice that I am
forcing you to take this action here again
the same action you took I am only saying
apply 80 okay, I am not allowing it to pick
again right, because if you pick again then
you are not on policy anymore because I use
80+1 to update here if I allow you to pick
another action you are not on policy anymore
because my value function has changed right.
I will be picking a different action so this
is slightly subtle things that right, but
here since I am taking the expectation it
does not matter I can go back and take a new
action and I can do this but this also makes
this may be kind of policy is it somewhere
in the gray region between on policy enough
policy because I am not actually evaluating
the action I took, right because at this point
I am not trying to even build the p right.
Let us just have a think about it a little
bit, right so at no point I am I having an
exclusive representation of a p anywhere in
this SARSA algorithm there is no policy here
and it is implicitly defined by the q functions
so when the q function changes the policy
is automatically changing right, but here
I am explicitly talking about the p so I have
to compute this p, right and then I have to
throw all of this in and then I can become
greedy with like epsilon greedy with respect
to the new q function I compute therefore
the p also will change every step right. So
apparently this has a name this is called
expected SARSA, okay fact I never came across
this until the second edition of the book
and I had to go back and see if there is actually
a paper on this but rich also cooks up things
for the book, right and all the off policy
Monte Carlo stuff that was there it never
used to exist before they wrote the first
edition of the book he just cooked it up for
the book okay, so like that he might have
cooked up this expected SARSA for the book
I am not sure but he just likes to add things.